There it is. The city-state of Karan.
I'd heard it was deep in the mountains...
But it's practically merged with them.
How'd they build a city
in the middle of the range?
You see, it was the other way around.
The city wasn't built in the mountains.
The mountains were built around the city.
They built the mountains?
The city was originally
founded in the Xarles era
as an outpost to defend against demons.
High-quality ore veins were
later discovered in the land below,
so we pushed the earth up
to bring them to the surface.
In other words, the mountains
themselves are the ore veins.
Huh. Ancient magic must've
really been something.
They have human riders.
That's the crest of the Gargan Empire.
Those are the empire's wyvern knights.
So they've tamed wyverns? Impressive.
What are they doing in Karan?
I hope it's got nothing to do
with what we're here for.
Let's get a move on too.
We are envoys from Zirgus.
We'd like an audience with the ambassador.
One moment, please.
Yes.
Understood.
There are a lot of dwarves here.
Elves and dwarves don't get along, right?
Th-Their disdain for us is entirely one-sided.
I've no strong feelings.
Thank you for waiting.
I am Miranda, the Zirgian ambassador.
You must be Queen Milena's messengers.
Delighted to meet you.
My name is Kyle Leonard.
Your reputation precedes you in Karan.
Please, right this way.
Miranda...
So she was serving as an ambassador
in Karan at this time.
I can confirm this letter is from the queen.
So, you're here to see the governor?
The nation may be in turmoil, but I never
expected such unusual messengers.
That's just like the new queen.
Are the two of you close?
Indeed. Until three years ago,
I was one of her tutors.
I mostly taught her diplomacy.
You have my sincere gratitude
for rescuing her in Archen.
However, the man you've
come to see, Governor Bax...
He's currently bedridden.
Getting an audience won't be easy.
The governor is that gravely ill?
I've asked to see him numerous times,
but I'm told he's not
taking visitors in his condition.
No visitors, huh?
However...
He has an obligation to meet
with emissaries from the queen.
Let's go.
Why does she need so many guards?
Maybe they're afraid
of what the empire might pull.
I don't need to be present
if we're just negotiating, right?
I'm gonna do my own thing.
Sure.
Be back before dark!
I'm not a child!
See you later.
It's an eyesore,
but this is the Gargan embassy.
Should anything happen there,
we will not be able to help you.
Exercise due caution.
Why, if it isn't Lady Miranda.
I wasn't expecting to see you here.
My, the Gargan ambassador himself.
How do you do?
My name is Alzard Vane.
I am the second-highest-ranking court
sorcerer of the Gargan Empire.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
I was on my way to see the governor of Karan.
Oh, really? Karan belongs to Zirgus.
As the Zirgian ambassador,
shouldn't I meet with him first?
Karan is a self-governing city-state.
I didn't think I needed Zirgus's permission.
They hate each other.
It would seem interhuman
diplomacy is also complicated.
We're actually on our way
to see the governor as well.
Why don't we go together?
I'd be delighted.
By the way, who might you be?
I am Kyle Leonard, emissary of Queen Milena.
Ah, so you're the hero of Zirgus.
I'd been wondering, since I heard
your name was Leonard.
You do look a bit like Ceraia.
You know my mother?
She and I were students together.
It's been twenty years now, but we studied
magic and other subjects side by side.
I am most pleased to have
the chance to meet her son.
Nice to meet you as well.
This job may be more fun than I expected.
Why can't we see him?
A-As I said, the governor
still hasn't recovered.
You've said that for two months.
If he's going to take much longer
to convalesce, then, as I've been suggesting,
we'll have to appoint a new governor.
Y-Yes, ma'am.
I'll return in two days.
I hope you'll have good news for me by then.
So, as you can see,
we cannot meet with the governor.
It certainly appears that way.
The empire was hoping to forge
a friendly relationship with Karan,
but I'll return another time.
He definitely knows the
engagement's being called off.
Yeah.
Coercion is the empire's go-to strategy.
I'm sure they'll begin issuing
all sorts of threats.
Alzard may even be trying to curry your favor.
So I'll appoint a new governor
better equipped to contend with the empire.
You already have someone in mind?
Yes.
A member of the blacksmith's guild
and Karan's best blacksmith.
His name is Gazus.
I should've known I wouldn't find anything
just looking around normally.
There aren't many girls around either.
Stop resisting!
Please stop! Let me go!
Just stop—
Are you hurt, miss?
I-I...
I'm a guy.
Y-You are?
Y-Yes, though I get mistaken for a girl a lot.
I can't believe myself...
Wh-Who the hell are you?
Mind your own business, outsider!
You're absolutely right.
Sorry for interrupting.
What?!
Y-You're not going to save me?
Hang on.
I have a question.
You got an older sister who looks like you?
Oh, yes. I have one who's five years older.
People say we look very much alike.
Prepare yourselves, scoundrels!
I'm about to give you a beating!
What?!
The hell is going on here?
Whatever! We can't let him beat us!
Get him!
This makes no sense.
Amazing.
I was prepared to run
if things went south, but...
I can hear you.
Th-Thank you so much!
My name is Goh.
I'm an artificer.
An artificer?
You make magic items?
Kinda.
Now then, who're these guys?
You see, they're debt collectors.
Debt collectors?
I see. Your parents must be drunkards
or gambling addicts who—
No, actually.
The debt is mine.
Then your parents are ill,
and to afford medicine—
It's not that either.
Then what is it?!
Their boss invested in a
magic weapon I'm developing,
but he got mad when I told him
it was going to take ten years to finish.
I see. So you're a way worse
person than your looks suggest.
Well, no skin off my nose.
For now, I'll escort you home.
Gotta introduce myself to your sister.
Oh, uh... my sister is already married.
Figures!
You should've led with that!
I thought you might not save me if I did.
Tee-hee.
You almost tricked me into
thinking you were cute!
H-How could you?!
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm a blacksmith.
I've no interest in any other line of work.
Gazus, Zirgus wants to provide
even more support to Karan
and work together to resolve our problems.
You don't need my help with that.
Please reconsider.
So that's Gazus, huh?
He's as stubborn as I expected.
You're popular among the people,
and you're more than qualified and capable.
This conversation is going nowhere.
It'll be tough to convince him.
Please, Gazus.
Appointing a dwarf as governor
is an absurd idea.
Dad, I'm home.
Oh, are you customers?
What're you guys doing here?
We're here accompanying Miranda.
I was invited to stop by for tea.
Apparently this dwarf named
Gazus is a skilled blacksmith.
If all goes well, he might
be able to make you a sword.
Seriously?
You were thinking about me?
Of course I was.
I intend to keep working you to the bone.
That's the Kyle we know and love.
Miranda's here?
This will take a while.
Why don't you come this way?
Sorry about the mess.
You look human, but your father
is a dwarf, which means...
Oh, I'm not a dwarf. I'm human.
Me and my sister were my mother's
children from a prior relationship.
Our mother passed away two years ago.
Since my sister got married a year ago,
the house has been a sty.
Oh, be careful.
That's a powerful adhesive that
can't be unstuck once applied.
Warn me sooner!
Oh, those are plans for the ancient
magic weapon I'm attempting to restore.
That was you?
Huh?
You're the creator of that golem?
What?
There exist autonomous magic
weapons known as golems.
Most of the technology required
to create them was lost when Xarles fell,
but towards the end of the Great Invasion,
the Gargan Empire deployed
a prototype against the demons
which achieved far more in battle
than humanoid soldiers ever could.
I see. This is well designed.
It's modeled off the Titan, yes?
You can tell?!
I made some improvements
based on ancient texts.
Indeed, there should be no issue swapping
the power source from magical to mundane.
What are the odds this'll work?
Very high, I'd say.
I can't believe it.
Mass-producing these would be
a huge boon to our forces!
Goh, you need to complete
this golem as soon as possible!
B-But it'll take another ten years, at least.
That's not fast enough!
Finish it within a year!
But that would cost an absurd amount of mon—
Then spend like there's no tomorrow!
I'll cover whatever you need!
What?!
Thank you for your business!
Also, keep this between us.
But I already have a few other investors.
Tell them you failed and return
their investments in full!
I'll cover all that too!
Really?!
All right!
I got myself a godly patron!
How did it go, Miranda?
We got nowhere.
Gazus, I'll be back again.
Don't bother.
Gazus, I'd like to make my own request.
You want a sword or something?
Sorry, but I'm only accepting jobs
from regulars right now.
Dad, at least hear him out.
I think these people will be really helpful.
Don't worry.
I'm not prejudiced against elves.
I-I see. That's commendable for a dwarf.
I'd like a sword.
My current one's not good enough.
Oh? Looks like Dortos's handiwork.
Not many swordsmen can say his blades
aren't good enough for them.
Dad, Theron is super strong.
I doubt that sword's enough for him.
What?
Ideally, I'd like one comparable to Kyle's.
Th-That sword...!
Let me take a closer look!
I've seen a few famous Xarles blades,
but this one's on another level.
I can't believe there was another one like it.
Another one?
I'm not currently able to make you
a sword comparable to this one.
I guess Sildonia's really that good.
But of course.
There's no greater sword
forged by humanoid hands.
Sorry, but you'll have to leave for today.
I wasn't expecting much,
but he said something curious.
About another sword like this one, right?
Which suggests he's seen
something close to it.
Close to me?
I won't stand for that!
We can come back tomorrow
and see if he'll say more.
It's too bad about the sword,
but the golem was a good find.
Indeed.
In my previous life, Goh must've
failed to recreate the weapon.
He went bankrupt
and had to sell his blueprints.
Then when the empire acquired them,
they were able to make a prototype
toward the end of the Great Invasion.
From a technological standpoint,
we should probably seek the empire's aid.
But if we share too much with them now,
they'll grow too powerful.
Queen Milena calling off the engagement
will wear on relations between our countries.
If we're not careful, war could break out
between humans before the Great Invasion.
I'd actually find that rather interesting.
Hey.
I'm joking.
Hello there.
Forgive the early morning visit.
I was thinking I'd like to chat
with the son of my old friend.
Okay...
Why don't we have lunch together later?
Your friends and the ambassador
are welcome to join us.
We could even cruise through
the skies on wyverns.
Are you sure?
I thought the skills to ride
them were a state secret.
Oh, you'll be fine.
It was Ceraia who established the
techniques for riding wyverns, after all.
My mother did?
Ceraia was quite talented.
I may be older, but I always
aspired to be like her.
Now she's just a lazy housewife.
I suppose that, too, is not unlike her.
Now then, I'll see you at the Gargan embassy.
I look forward to lunch.
I thought so yesterday as well,
but his magic power is substantial.
You can tell?
Yes. He's got enough to cast high-level spells.
He may even be able to cast
special-grade spells someday.
Special-grade spells?
The empire's court sorcerers are no joke.
The others didn't need to come?
They're not fond of formal meals.
Kyle?
This feeling...
What?
Kyle, what is the—
Demon!
Next Time
Those Who Act Out of Sight
Next time: "Those Who Act Out of Sight."